A Finding Aid to the Museum of Craft and Folk Art Records, 1970-2012, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition Files, 1976-2012; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 22.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-24; 12.14 Gigabytes ER03-ER50
  - Pie Ranch, movies by Robin Moore, Andy Miller and Lauren Reppy, Digital Video Recordings, 2011; Archival Resource Key; 1.41 Gigabytes Four computer files (Folder ER49)
    Films included: Eat Pie, Share the Pie, Teach Pie, and The Whole Pie.
  - Guest Register for Design for Living and J. B. Blunk Exhibitions, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Guest Register for Pie Farms and Fiber Futures Exhibitions, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Exhibitions at Other Museums and Galleries, Archival Resource Key (Box 23)
    - Hamburg - Metis Art Show, circa 1985-circa 1995; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - The Figure in Nature (1989), Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Del Mano Gallery - Ron Kent: The Translucent Bowl (1996), Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Smithsonian - American Glass: Masters of the Art (1999), circa 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Galeria H & H Exhibitions, Digital Documents, 2006; Archival Resource Key; 0.112 Gigabytes Five computer files (Folder ER50)
- Artists' Files, 1983-2007; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 24
  Artists' files includes resumes and inquiries from artists interested in exhibiting at the MOCFA but not necessarily represented by the museum, which were kept on file for reference, along with several recordings of artists, probably performances or interviews or studio tours, that were not clearly related to any exhibition. There are 8 videocassettes (VHS) and 1 electronic disk (CD).
  - Artist Resumes and Inquiries, 1983-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
  - Bean, Bennett, 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Bennett, Jaime and Robert Ebendorf, circa 1985-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Fasanella, Ralph, circa 1985-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Graham, Bill, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Kovatch, Ron, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Moran, Mike, circa 1985-circa 1995; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Ricalde, Salvador V., 2007; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (CD) Transfer not possible. (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Museum of Craft and Folk Art Publications, 1977-2012; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 24-25, OV 31-32; 0.003 Gigabytes ER51
  Museum of Craft and Folk Art (MOCFA) publications include exhibition catalogs, newsletters, reports, and announcements published by the MOCFA. There are also 4 videocassettes and some born digital material of exhibition images and events at the museum that were recorded by MOCFA.
  - A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1977-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1986-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Oversized material housed in OV 31.
  - A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum Bound Volume, 1986-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum, 2004-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Artifacts, 2000-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1983-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 2006-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Event Invitations, 1994-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1984-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1989-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key; Includes born digital records, see ER51. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Digital Photographs and Documents, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.003 Gigabytes 11 computer files (Folder ER51)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Riches from Rags, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Fashion Shows, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - A Stitch in Time, circa 1985-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified "SF Craft and Folk Art Museum" Recording, circa 1985-circa 1995; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Betacam) (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Issues of A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum from Box 24, Folder 15, 1986-2003; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 31)
  - Oversized Bound Volume of A Report from the San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum from Box 24, Folder 16, 1986-2003; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 32)
- Printed Material and Commercial Video Recordings, 1983-2007; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 2.7 Linear feet Boxes 26-28, OV 33-35; 0.05 Gigabytes ER52
  Printed materials and video recordings includes an oversized scrapbook (disbound) of clippings and photographs about the museum's early exhibitions, several (disbound) binders of exhibition press clippings, clippings on assorted subjects maybe intended for research on exhibition ideas, documentaries on artists published by third parties, and news coverage of exhibitions. There are 17 videocassettes, 1 sound cassette, and 1 born digital video recording.
  - Scrapbook, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in OV 33-35.
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1983-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 11-13)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14-16)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings Binder, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1-10)
  - Exhibition Press Clippings, 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements from Other Galleries and Museums, 1989-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs of Other Galleries and Museums, 1994-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, Archival Resource Key (Box 27)
    - Museum of Craft and Folk Art New Location, 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Amish Quilts, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Calligraphy, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Kahlo, Frida, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Documentaries, 1987-1991; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Documentaries, 1991-1999; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Documentaries, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Documentary, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - News Program Coverage, circa 1989-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - News Program Coverage, circa 1989; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - News Program Coverage, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - News Program Coverage, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - News Program Coverage, 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - News Program Coverage, 2002-2006; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Includes born digital records, see ER52.
  - Museum of Craft and Folk Art, ABC News at 6:00, KGO-TV Ch. 7, San Francisco, February 13, 2006, Digital Video Recording, 2019; Archival Resource Key; 0.05 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER52)
  - Oversized Scrapbook from Box 26, Folder 1, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 33)
  - Oversized Scrapbook from Box 26, Folder 1, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 34)
  - Oversized Scrapbook from Box 26, Folder 1, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
- Photographic Materials, 1970-2011; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 28-30; 0.282 Gigabytes ER53
  Photographic materials include slides, negatives, printed and digital photographs, and transparencies. There is a disbound album of exhibition installations and events, slides of crafts from different geographic regions (titles in quotation marks reflect the original labels of materials), slides of artwork from exhibitions, portraits of artists, snapshots of events such as auctions and openings, and photographs of MOCFA offices and staff.
  - Album of People Installing Museum of Craft and Folk Art Exhibitions, 1983-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - "Central Asia" Costumes and Textiles Slides from Binder, 1973-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
  - "Contemporary Crafts - Textiles" Slides, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
  - "Hungary" Costumes Slides, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - "Middle East" Costumes and Textiles Slides, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - "Tibet" Artifacts, Costumes, Ritual Objects Slide from Binder, 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Slides of Artwork from Exhibitions, 1983-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1-4)
  - Photographs of Artwork from Exhibitions, circa 1982-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Artwork from Exhibitions, circa 1990-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 6-13)
    Series of black and white photographs (18 cm x 13 cm) of artwork, maybe used for reference.
  - Slides of Artwork from Anneberg Gallery Exhibitions, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Transparencies of Artwork by Various Artists, 1992-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Portraits of Artists, Archival Resource Key (Box 29)
    - Gonzalez-Chavajay, Lorenzo, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Jimenez, Nicario, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Lovering-Brown, T., 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Sebastian, Barbara, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Trinkkeller, Ed, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 20)
      Copy print of photograph that was originally taken circa 1927.
    - Wood, Beatrice, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - A Frida! Fashion Theater and Art Auction, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Museum of Craft and Folk Art Benefit Auction, circa 1990-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Museum of Craft and Folk Art Offices and Work Stations, circa 1985-circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Museum of Craft and Folk Art Staff, circa 1985-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Craft and Folk Art Opening, Digital Photographs, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.282 Gigabytes 72 computer files (Folder ER53)
  - "1st Quarter 2002" Photographs of People, Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - People at Events and Openings, 1995-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Stocksdale, Bob and Kay Sekimachi, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 8)
    Snapshots at parties and events.
  - Miscellaneous Negatives, circa 1985-circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Snapshots of Artwork, circa 1998-circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 10)